Joe Gallant Web Designer / Developer



Telephone: 07984 567668

Email: joe@jgallant.co.uk

D.O.B: 09/03/1995

Web: www.jgallant.co.uk

Address: 56 Springfields, Great Dunmow, Essex, England. CM6 1BS

@JoeGallant95

joe-gallant

Profile

I am a young, enthusiastic worker with a big passion for web design and development. I would consider myself to be more of a front-end developer with an intermediate understanding of back-end development. Web design and development has been a passion of mine ever since leaving high school, it began more as a hobby but soon turned into a realistic career path. I began by teaching myself the basics in my spare time from books to online video tutorials. From there I landed my first job in the industry as an apprentice web developer for a small graphic design agency based in Sawston, Cambridgeshire. To view my portfolio of work you can visit my site – www.jgallant.co.uk

Experience

Red Graphic

Web Designer / Developer

2014 - present

I currently work at Red Graphic, a small graphic design agency based in Sawston, Cambridge. I started at Red Graphic as an apprentice web developer working with the senior developer on all web projects. After the first year went by I had finished my apprenticeship and they took me on as a full time web developer. Currently I am the only web developer working for the company and I have the responsibility of all things web. This includes meeting with clients and taking briefs, creating innovative design concepts that match those briefs, developing responsive websites that meet the W3C standards, implementing new SEO changes, managing all clients domains and hosting, setting up and maintaining emails. As well as dealing with all web projects I also dipped in and out of various different graphic design tasks such as designing business cards, letterheads, comp slips and flyers.

Experience

The Co-Operative

Team Member 2011 - 2014

I worked for the Co-Operative supermarket for three years and the work there has taught me great customer service, handling cash, working towards deadlines, to work within a team and also as an individual.

Skills

- HTML
- CSS (Sass)
- Javascript / jQuery
- Wordpress

- GitHub
- Bootstrap
- Adobe CS
- PHP

Education

Red Graphic

Sawston, Cambridgeshire, England. 2014 - 2015

Cambridge Regional College

Cambridge, Cambridgeshire, England. 2012 - 2014

Helena Romanes School

Great Dunmow, Essex, England. 2006- 2011

Qualifications

Red Graphic

- Advanced Apprenticeship in IT, Software, Web & Telecoms
- BTffEC Level 3 Diploma in Professional Competence for IT & Telecoms Professionals (QCF) (x2)
- BTEC Level 3 Diploma in ICT Systems and Principles (QCF) (x2)

Cambridge Regional College

- BTEC Level 3 Diploma in Media.

Helena Romanes School

- 10 GCSEs